<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-09T23:04:33-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Michael Eisemann’s Personal Site</title><subtitle>You've made it this far, why not read more?</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to set up and use an IME</title><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/31-How_To_Setup_An_IME" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to set up and use an IME" /><published>2019-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/31-How_To_Setup_An_IME</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/31-How_To_Setup_An_IME">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-set-up-an-ime-on-macos-windows-linux-ios-and-android&quot;&gt;How to set up an IME on macOS, Windows, Linux, iOS, and Android.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#macos&quot;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#windows&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#linux&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ios&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction-&quot;&gt;Introduction &lt;a name=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am making this blog post because after reading the instructions on setting up Japanese Input Method Editor (IME) sensei has on the main blog page, I felt like a more up to date instruction set would not hurt. This blog post shows you how to set up Japnaese input on almost all major platforms, but when in dobut, do a little research on your own or feel free to get in contact with me. I would be more than happy to help anyone having difficulties getting things set up. You can shoot me an email using the E-Mail link or dropping a comment on this page. I’ll do my best to respond to anyone having difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;macos-&quot;&gt;macOS &lt;a name=&quot;macos&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fairly simple to set up and use the Japanese IME on macOS. This guide is written while using macOS 10.15, but it should apply to most recent versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Open System Preferences to ‘Keyboard’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/ae8.pn&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Choose the ‘Input Sources’ Tab and click the ‘+’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/M.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Select Japanese from this list, and click add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/qc.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go, you’ve succesfully added the Japanese IME on macOS. But, how do you use it? It’s fairly simple, actually. To switch input methods, hit ‘Control’ and ‘Space at the same time. What this does is switch your input to Hiragana, but typed using Romaji. The instructions sensei handed out in class on 08/30/2019 are good enough to get started using a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows-&quot;&gt;Windows &lt;a name=&quot;windows&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Japanese IME on Windows 10 is very, very different than the one from macOS. It’s a little unintuitive, but I’ve made it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Go to the Windows settings by clicking on the gear icon in the Windows menu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Select ‘Time and Language’ and then ‘Language’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/anf.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Click Add Language and Select Japanese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: You most likely don’t want to set Japanese to be your Windows Display Language, so go ahead and keep only ‘Install language pack’ selected. Then hit ‘Install’. From there, Windows will download and install the Japanese Language Pack. This could take a bit of time depending on your connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 4: You should now see ‘ENG’ in your task bar. To switch to Japanese, hit Windows + Space at the same time. It should change to an ‘A’ and a ‘J’. This means alphanumeric input, which is essentially the same thing as English input. To switch to kana input push ‘Alt’ and ‘~’ at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/Pr.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 5: The most confusing part for me is that every application on your computer will have different language settings. This is a big difference between the default one for macOS. For example, if I’m using Microsoft Word in Japanese input, and then switch to Google Chrome, my input method switches back to English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again sensei’s instructions should be able to help you actually use the IME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;linux-&quot;&gt;Linux &lt;a name=&quot;linux&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is a very big can of worms. Almost every distribution is different and each application framework will work differently with whatever IME you choose. I personally use &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/IBus#Japanese&quot;&gt;Arch Linux using ibus + anthy&lt;/a&gt;, but since most people using Linux who would be reading this guide are probably using Ubuntu, I will target Ubuntu 18.04. For this section in particular, please reach out to me for any help, since I personally use Linux every day and can help anyone who is having troubles. I’ll update this section as I get things working, so just hang tight. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ios-&quot;&gt;iOS &lt;a name=&quot;ios&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is fairly simple to get the Japanese IME on iOS. This will be done using an iPhone XS running iOS 13.1, but should apply to all iOS devices regardless of model and version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Go to Settings, then General, then Keyboards, and then Keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Hit ‘Add New Keyboard…’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Select ‘Japanese’ and then Romaji. Now, click ‘Done’ in the top right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that simple. To make Japanese your active keyboard. Go to the textbox you’d like to input text into, and then click the Globe icon on your keyboard. This will switch between English and Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/dp.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;android-&quot;&gt;Android &lt;a name=&quot;android&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize ahead of time if the instructions are out of date for this section. I haven’t used an Android phone in some time, but I think for the most part, things here should be still relevant. Worst case, search for your specific device model and typing in Japanese. This section is also currently a WIP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is done on a Nexus 5, running Android 4.4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Go to the Play Store and search for the ‘Google Japanese Input’ and install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Find the newly installed app on your device and follow the instructions. It will ask you to enable the method for your device, and select it as your input method. Do these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Now, go back to the app and select ‘Keyboard Layout’ at the top. Then slide the layout over to ‘QWERTY’. This will allow you to type with Romaji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. There are some things you will want to know. To switch between your English and Japanese layouts, most phones will place a globe in the Notification Shade for you to select which input you want to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun with your new input method!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;just-comments&quot; data-apikey=&quot;32afe1ae-50af-4d5b-be82-b3f37d48e922&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://just-comments.com/w2.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="japanese" /><summary type="html">How to set up an IME on macOS, Windows, Linux, iOS, and Android.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going to an Upcoming Anime Film!</title><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/Going_To_an_Upcoming_Anime_Film" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going to an Upcoming Anime Film!" /><published>2019-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/Going_To_an_Upcoming_Anime_Film</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190908/Going_To_an_Upcoming_Anime_Film">&lt;h1 id=&quot;going-to-an-upcoming-anime-film&quot;&gt;Going to an Upcoming Anime Film!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just bought tickets to go see &lt;a href=&quot;https://rascaldoesnotdream.com/&quot;&gt;Seishun Buta Yarō wa Yumemiru Shōjo no Yume o Minai (Rascal Does Not Dream of a Dreaming Girl)&lt;/a&gt; at AMC River East 21 in Chicago for Thursday, October 3, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the main series anime this show was based off, &lt;a href=&quot;https://anilist.co/anime/101291/Seishun-Buta-Yarou-wa-Bunny-Girlsenpai-no-Yume-wo-Minai/&quot;&gt;Seishun Buta Yarou wa Bunny Girl-senpai no Yume wo Minai&lt;/a&gt;, and I just have to go see the movie. If anyone else is interested in going with me, I would be happy to drive up to 3 other people to see the movie with me, all you need to do is purchase your ticket. I know the middle of the week isn’t the best day to go see a movie nearly 2 hours away, but there are no other closer threaters. I also am aware that a lot of people have exams during this week (because I do), but all mine are earlier in the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are at all interested in going, please fill out this Google Form: &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/BtX8TuxYF2bU5wgj7&quot;&gt;https://forms.gle/BtX8TuxYF2bU5wgj7&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="japanese" /><summary type="html">Going to an Upcoming Anime Film!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019年08月29日 ブログ – Welcome to my Blog!</title><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190827/Japanese_1_Frist_Post" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019年08月29日 ブログ -- Welcome to my Blog!" /><published>2019-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190827/Japanese_1_Frist_Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190827/Japanese_1_Frist_Post">&lt;h1 id=&quot;私のブログへようこそ-welcome-to-my-blog&quot;&gt;私のブログへようこそ！／ Welcome to my blog!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;こんいちは！ マイケルです。私はアニメ、コンピューター、J-POPが好きです。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there, my name is Mike Eisemann. I’m 20 years old and a Junior at the University of Notre Dame studying computer science. Some of my interests are anime, computers/video games, and music, specifically J-POP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite anime are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Lucky Star&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Darling in the Franxx&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Gabriel Dropout&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/Oq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lucky Star&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/uy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Darling in the Franxx&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/af1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gabriel Dropout&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have much time for anime or much other as of late, mainly due to my course load increasing. However, when I do have time, I have been watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://anilist.co/anime/107663/Kanata-no-Astra/&quot;&gt;Kanata no Astra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some information about me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I am from the small town of Galesburg, Illinois, which is about 4 hours south of Chicago and sort of in the middle of nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I only got interested in Japan and Japanese during my freshman year of college. Before then, all I had known about Japan was that my grandfather served in the military during the United States’ occupation of Japan after World War II. I have since fallen in love with the language and the rich, rich history and culture of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I love computers and love to run my own web services whenever possible. For example, this blog runs entirely using &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; running off of a computer I configured myself. I find it very fun to face the challenges some of the DIY projects bring. I’ve also got a file sharing/link shortening service at &lt;a href=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/&quot;&gt;https://waifupaste.moe/&lt;/a&gt;. It’s pretty fun to make things work with computers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I regularly listen to J-POP/Japanese music. Some of my favorite songs are:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;君のせい by ‘the peggies’&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;言いて。 by ‘ヨルシカ’&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Mousou Express from the MONOGATARI Series&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/V9.mp2&quot;&gt;Click here to listen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/Mz.mp2&quot;&gt;Click here to listen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://waifupaste.moe/raw/xz.mp2&quot;&gt;Click here to listen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to discuss anything Japanese pop-culture, feel free to get in contact with me. I would be more than happy to meet new people who are interested in the same things I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-expectations-and-thoughts-on-this-class&quot;&gt;My Expectations and Thoughts on this Class&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hope to learn a lot during this semester. I’ve self studied bits and pieces of Japanese over the past couple years, and even purchased books such as Japanese for Busy People and GENKI I, but never had some of the self-discipline to really put my nose to the grind stone. 
I think that formally taking a class will make me  put in the extra effort to achieve more. I’m excited to go through the long and strenuous journey that is learning Japanese with you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;just-comments&quot; data-apikey=&quot;32afe1ae-50af-4d5b-be82-b3f37d48e922&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://just-comments.com/w2.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="japanese" /><summary type="html">私のブログへようこそ！／ Welcome to my blog!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tugboat</title><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190724/tugboat" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tugboat" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190724/tugboat</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190724/tugboat">&lt;h1 id=&quot;tugboat&quot;&gt;Tugboat&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tiny application that will sync your git repos if you want them to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the idea for something similar to this when I first deployed this website. I wanted to be able to keep everything self hosted, but also lightweight. I was told I should investigae using something like Travis CI, GitLab CI/CD, or Jenkins, but I really wasn’t liking those ideas for a couple of reasons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Travis CI isn’t free&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;GitLab CI/CD or public Jenkins would require SSH access into my box&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jenkins is too overkill for what I wanted to do&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, using my knowledge building another website with tornado, I made tugboat. I think it was a good exercise of warming myself back up to real Python developing since leaving school for the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find tugboat on github here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AndroidKitKat/tugboat&quot;&gt;https://github.com/AndroidKitKat/tugboat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Tugboat</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Projects</title><link href="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190722/projects" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Projects" /><published>2019-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190722/projects</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.michaeleisemann.com/20190722/projects">&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-projects&quot;&gt;My Projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get more time, I’m going to flesh this page out, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">My Projects</summary></entry></feed>